# LAUREN PALMER

lpalmer@live.com

Portfolio: https://lpalmer2c8e.myportfolio.com Github: https://github.com/lepalmer01 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/le-p

With over 6 years of experience, I blend front-end development and marketing into my UX/UI design expertise, focusing on creating responsive, user-centered interfaces. My skills in design thinking and visual communication allow for effective project management and innovative solution delivery, all while maintaining a keen eye on user experience and strategic objectives.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Marketing Associate, Accelor Corp DBA Supply Risk Solutions

February 2021 to Present

- Develops and maintains marketing videos and software tutorials using Adobe Premiere and After Effects, strategically highlighting software functionalities for the healthcare and semiconductor sectors, enhancing user engagement and product comprehension.
- Optimizes website functionality and design to elevate user experience, aligning enhancements with business objectives while prioritizing user-centric approaches. Employed software such as Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign and Figma
- Reviews current events and hot topics, assigning relevance and importance to these topics and current events to improve development of AI technology in customer news feeds.
- Collaborates closely with CEO and healthcare executives in weekly meetings to discuss and proactively identify emerging threats within the healthcare industry, emphasizing strategic foresight for business resilience.
- Authors news articles on potential supply chain disruptions in the semiconductor and healthcare fields, integrating user research and analytics to provide valuable content that informs and educates on emerging disruptions.

# Blum Summer Field Internship Mentor, UCSD Center on Global Justice

June 2023 to August 2023

- Selected for the 2022 Blum Summer Field Internship at EarthLab Community Station in Southeast San Diego. Co-designed and
  facilitated a climate justice education curriculum with copartners Groundworks San Diego and Millennial Tech Middle School for
  students in grades 6-8.
- Engaged in innovative mentorship programming with local youth and collaborated with fellow interns to research community challenges, including health, urban development, public space, environmental justice, education, climate action, human rights, arts, and youth leadership.
- Summarized findings and proposed recommendations for the future of EarthLab programming.

## Domestic Violence Advocate, Human Options

July 2020 to September 2021

- Assessed 24-hour hotline caller's needs and provided appropriate referrals for community programs and services.
- Screened callers applying for the Domestic Violence Emergency Shelter and completed Emergency Shelter intakes while ensuring to implement principles of trauma-informed care.
- Supervised the Emergency Shelter facility and security, serving as first point of contact for 15 clients and providing immediate crisis services to onsite residents.
- Collaborated with local partners, including law enforcement, social services, and non-profit chapters on filling immediate, short-term, and long-term needs of clients, including shelter and food.
- Coordinate with various mental health experts on providing trauma-informed services to callers and residents on a monthly basis to assure all emotional needs are tended to properly.

#### Freelance Photographer, Independent Contractor

July 2019 to Present

- Employed Adobe Photoshop, Camera Raw, Bridge, and Lightroom to edit photographs for clients on a monthly basis, seeing to it that all edits were in accordance with client preference.
- Incorporated customer service skills to establish relationships with clients, leading to 95% growth in referral business.
- Maintain a strong understanding of current photography trends and techniques.
- Coordinated the scheduling and logistics of photo shoots, including selecting suitable locations and ensuring timely setup, resulting in smooth operations and client satisfaction.

## Office Manager, Architecture Firm

February 2018 to October 2019

- Spearheaded process improvements in organizational systems and procedures for office staff, enhancing filing and bookkeeping efficiency, resulting in a 25% increase in productivity.
- Implemented new time tracking software for payroll management, significantly improving efficiency by 35%.
- Negotiated contracts with contractors and subcontractors without the need for legal escalation.
- Leveraged people management skills to cultivate and strengthen relationships with local organizations and clients, enhancing partnership networks.
- Managed multiple client accounts simultaneously, maintaining high levels of satisfaction and engagement. Assumed leadership for project management and team coordination, effectively identifying and mitigating potential vulnerabilities.

## Server, Public74

July 2017 to July 2018

- Achieved a 95% customer satisfaction rate through effective interpersonal communication, establishing strong rapport with an average of 30 customers daily.
- Expertly guided guests through menus, leveraging in-depth knowledge of over 30 beverage items and daily specials.
- Ensured the cleanliness and sanitation of tables, stockroom, windows, and floors across a 2000 square foot dining area, meeting and exceeding safety and sanitation standards.
- Collaborated with a team of 10 co-workers to enhance operational efficiency, leading to a 15% improvement in table turnover rate.

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

### Full Stack Web Development Certificate

University of California-San Diego Extended Studies

## Bachelor of Arts in Speculative Design

University of California-San Diego

#### Level 1 Foundation Training Certificate

Foundation Training Ltd.

#### Associate of Arts in Human Expression and Social Sciences

Fullerton College

#### **SKILLS & TOOLS**

**Coding:** React, JavaScript, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Object Oriented Programming, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, MVC Framework, Express,

Apollo, MongoDB

Design: ZBrush, Adobe Creative Cloud Suite, Disco Diffusion, Video Editing & Production, Marketing

Soft Skills: Excellent Communicator, Adaptable, Negotiable, Organized, Project Management